Guide to the Robert Sutherland Lord Papers, 1890-2013 UA.90.F101
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Robert Sutherland Lord Papers
1890-2016
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Lord, Robert Sutherland, Dr.
UA.90.F101
18 Linear Feet
This collection consists of the personal and professional papers of Dr. Robert Sutherland Lord, a prominent organist based at the University of Pittsburgh. As one of the few students of Jean Langlais, Dr. Lord became a prominent scholar on nineteenth and twentieth century French organ music and the foremost authority on French organist and composer, Charles Tournemire. Dr. Lord served as the chapel organist at the Heinz Memorial Chapel in addition to his teaching responsibilities in the Music Department and was responsible for both the 1971 and the 1995 renovations of the chapel organ. Over Dr. Lord's 37 year tenure with the University of Pittsburgh he gave approximately 160 organ concerts, his most popular classes attracted over 800 students per year, and he played for over 4,000 weddings.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift from the Lord family on December 15, 2014.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into nine series as follows:
Series I. Biographical Material
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Writings and Notes
Series IV. Research Files
Series V. Departmental and Administrative Files
Series VI. Professional Associations
Series VII. Printed Materials
Series VIII. Photographic Materials
Series IX. Audio Material
The collection is arranged into nine series as follows:
Series I. Biographical Material Series II. Correspondence Series III. Writings and Notes Series IV. Research Files Series V. Departmental and Administrative Files Series VI. Professional Associations Series VII. Printed Materials Series VIII. Photographic Materials Series IX. Audio Material
Biography
Dr. Robert Sutherland Lord (1930-2014) was a prominent organist based at the University of Pittsburgh. Dr. Lord was born and raised in Marblehead, Massachusetts, and began studying organ at the age of five. By age 12, he was regularly playing at the Clifton Lutheran Church in Marblehead. Dr. Lord received his bachelor's degree in Music from Dartmouth College in 1952 and his Master's and Ph.D. in History of Music from Yale University in 1960. Dr. Lord's organ education was shaped by prominent musical figures from an early age, beginning with Maurice Longhurst in 1948. For his dissertation study, Dr. Lord moved to Paris, France, to study organ improvisation with Jean Langlais, who was one of the few students of Charles Tournemire; Touremire in turn was a student of César Franck. Dr. Lord was exceptionally proud of this musical lineage and under their instruction he performed at the Basilica of Sainte-Clotilde in Paris, the Cathedrals of Notre-Dame in Paris and in Chartres, and at King's College in Cambridge. Later in his professional career, Dr. Lord took a sabbatical in order to learn Bach and Reger in Hamburg, Germany with Heinz Wunderlich.
After graduating from Yale, Dr. Lord taught at Davidson College in North Carolina before being hired by the University of Pittsburgh for the Heinz Memorial Chapel Organist position in 1962. Dr. Lord received tenure in 1963 and began teaching a full course load in addition to his performance responsibilities. Over the following three decades, Dr. Lord took up a number of administrative roles within the Music Department including Director of Graduate Studies from 1975 to 1978 and Chairperson from 1984 to 1987. In addition to performing approximately 160 organ concerts, Dr. Lord published extensively on Tournemire. His first major publication was Liturgy and Gregorian Chant in L'Orgue Mystique of Charles Tournemire, which was published in 1984. In 1989, he was commissioned by the director of the music library at the Bibliothèque Nationale de France to undertake the analysis and eventual publication of a musical manuscript of Tournemire's that originally extended over 1,300 pages. This book, Catalogue of Charles Tournemire's 'Brouillon' [Rough Sketches] for L'Orgue Mystique, BNF., Mus., Ms. 19929, was finally published in 2014, one month before his death.
One of Dr. Lord's most recognized achievements was spear-heading both the 1971 and the 1995 organ renovations in Heinz Memorial Chapel and the 1965 organ renovation in the Henry Clay Frick Fine Arts Building.
Alongside his professional academic career, Dr. Lord was actively involved in the music community, particularly the American Musicological Society, the Organ Historical Society, and the American Guild of Organists. In a more personal capacity, Dr. Lord served as the organist and choirmaster at Christ Episcopal Church in the North Hills for 22 years and served as the first Chairman of the Board of the Northland Public Library.
Dr. Lord retired from teaching in 1999 and gave a final concert in Heinz Chapel that was attended by almost 600 students, faculty, and staff. By his request, Dr. Lord remained the Head Organist for Heinz Chapel long after his formal separation from the University. Dr. Lord died on July 24, 2014, at the age of 84.
Previous Citation
Robert Sutherland Lord Papers, 1890-2013, UA.90.F101, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
This collection documents the professional career of Dr. Robert Sutherland Lord as an organist both within the University of Pittsburgh and in the greater music community. The collection begins with general biographical information about his personal life and offers insight into his family. The bulk of the collection contains personal, professional, and University related correspondence and materials from Dr. Lord's work as the University Organist at Heinz Chapel, his research files, and his collection of performance records. These records span a wide variety of document types and formats including books, sheet music, correspondence, teaching files, programs, and audio recordings.
Significant materials include photos, rare books, and sheet music composed by either Tournemire or Langlais; correspondence with the Frick and Heinz families; letters and blueprints concerning the Heinz Memorial Chapel and the Frick Fine Arts Building organ renovations; unpublished book and article manuscripts; and a number of audio recordings that feature both his concerts in Heinz Chapel and his weekly program series on WQED-FM called "Lord on Bach." Other materials found in this collection consist of Dr. Lord's performance records in various churches which are primarily in the form of weekly church bulletins. However, the most involved body of materials in this collection are Dr. Lord's research files on Tournemire.
organs (aerophones); Music -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Organ music; University of Pittsburgh; Lord, Robert Sutherland, Dr.; Longhurst, Maurice; University of Pittsburgh. Music Department; Heinz Memorial Chapel (University of Pittsburgh); Tournemire, Charles; Langlais, Jean
- Biographical Material, 1948-2016; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains short autobiographies, Dr. Lord's degrees and records from Dartmouth and Yale and annotated resumes and curriculum vitae through the mid-1980s. Lord's educational records also include materials from his studies in Paris at the Institut de France.
  - "About the Performer" Biographies (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Douglas D. Himes article, "Robert Sutherland Lord and The Sainte-Clotilde Tradition," The American Organist, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Professional Resumes and Curriculum Vitae (Various Drafts), 1982-1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Marblehead High School Yearbook, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 50th High School Reunion, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dartmouth School Books, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dartmouth Class Book and 25th Reunion Book, 1952-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Military Records, 1953-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Institut de France Papers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dartmouth Papers, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yale Records, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Degrees and Certificates, 1954 (Box 14, Oversize 1)
    - Masters Degree from Yale University, 1952-1960; 1.
    - Doctorate Degree from Yale University, 1960; 2.
    - Undergraduate Degree from Dartmouth, 1952; 3.
    - Associate Certificate from the American Guild of Organists, 1952; 4.
- Correspondence, 1950-2012; II.
  This series provides a general reference to Dr. Lord's affairs both personally and professionally. The correspondence tracks his involvement with various organizations and churches. Significant personal correspondence can be found between Dr. Lord and Helen Clay Frick, the Heinz family, Jean Langlais, and Charles Tournemire's widow. Significant professional correspondence illustrates Dr. Lord's work within the Music Department at the University of Pittsburgh, with various Deans and Chancellors, and concerning the renovations of Heinz Chapel.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1950-2012; 1.
    - Correspondence: A, 1961-1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Archbold, Lawrence, 1958-2012 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: B, 1958-2012 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: C, 1958-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Christ Church, 1964-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: D, 1969-2013 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Donelson, Jennifer, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: E, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: F, 1959-1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Frick, Helen, 1966-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: G, 1963-1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: H, 1961-2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: Hakim, Naji, 1998-2006 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: Heinz Family, 1971-1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence: Hobbs, Alain, 1974-1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: I-J, 1963-1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence: K, 1956-1996 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: L, 1965-1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: La Trinite, Paris, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: Langlais, 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Langlais, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Langlais, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: Langlais, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence: Langlais, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence: Lord Family, 1969-2012 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: M, 1964-1999 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: Messiaen, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence: Methuen Music Hall, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence: N, 1993-1999 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence: Noehren, Robert, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence: O, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: P, 1966-2012 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence: R, 1963-1999 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence: Royal Music Association Conference, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence: S, 1959-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Schloesser, Stephen, 2004-2014 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Selective Military Service Office, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: T, 1970-2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Tomlinson and Hatch, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Madame Tournemire, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Madame Tournemire, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Madame Tournemire, 1989-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: U-W, 1962-2012 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: X-Z, 1957-1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Unknown Authors, 1964-2007 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Professional Correspondence, 1957-2007; 2.
    - American Organist Guild, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Dartmouth, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Davidson College, 1958-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Other Universities, 1968-1999 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Yale, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Other Universities, 1961-2007 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - University Correspondence, 1962-2008; 3.
    - Frick Fine Arts Organ Renovation, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Heinz Chapel Organ Renovation, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Heinz Chapel, 1986-1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Events and Publications, 1972-1999 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Music Department, 1966-2008 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Chancellor Mark Nordenberg, 1994-1999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Other University of Pittsburgh Departments, 1968-1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Chancellor Wesley Posvar, 1967-1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Dean Jerome Rosenberg, 1964-1983 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - University of Pittsburgh Faculty, 1962-2006 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Frick Fine Arts Organ & Concert Funds, 1962-1967 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Other Organs, 1964-1973 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Writings and Notes, 1954-2007; III.
  This series primarily consists of articles that were published or reviewed by Dr. Lord, research proposals, and various research notes and notebooks including his research on the specifications of other organs in preparation for the renovation of the Heinz Chapel organ. The majority of the articles found in this series reflect his research interests in Sainte Clotilde, Charles Tournemire, Jean Langlais, liturgy and Gregorian chant, and other popular topics within the organ music community. Significant items within this series include a manuscript version of a 1991 article "Jean Langlais, the Teacher" and "Liturgy and Gregorian Chant in L'Orgue Mystique."
  - Graduate Academic Notes: Yale, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Graduate Academic Notes: Yale, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Graduate Academic Notes: Institut de France, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Article: "Sources of Past Serve Langlais in Organ Works", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Article: "Organ Music of Jean Langlais", 1968 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Notebook, ca. 1971 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Article: "The Saint-Clothilde Traditions- Franck, Tournemire and Langlais: Conversation and Commentary with Jean Langlais", March 1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Article: "Remnants of an Early E. and G.G. Hook Organ", Spring 1975 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Article: "First Carnegie Pipe Organ", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Article: "Charles Tournemire & The Seven Words Christ said on the Cross" (in English and French), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Article: "John Roberts Philadelphia and Cambridgeport Organ Builder (1850-1877)", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Article: "Jean Langlais honore par une universite americaine", ca. 1977 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Article: "Jean Langlais- on the Occasion of His Seventieth Birthday", February 1977 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Article: "International Concours for Organ at Chartres", November 1980 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Article: "The Liturgical Function of the Organ in France After the Motu Proprio of 1903", October 1983 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Article: "University Organist Reflects on Bach's Influence", February 1985 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Notes (Various), ca. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Article: "The Second International Academy of Organ", July 1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Article: "Liturgy and Gregorian Chant in L'Orgue Mystique", 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Article: "Jean Langlais, The Teacher", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Notes on "Fifth International Organ Academy", ca. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Article: "Fifth International Organ Academy in Paris", June 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Book Review: Darkness & Light", October 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Notes on L'Eglise Sainte Clothilde, ca. 1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Research Notes, ca. 1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Article: "The 1993 Rebuilding of the Cavaille-Coll Organ in the Basilica of Saint Clothilde, Paris: Tournemire's Blueprint for the Console", 2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Article: "Conrad Pauman and the Organ Repertory of the Lochamer Liederburgh" (Research included), undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Essay: "The Suite Medievale: Jean Langlais and the 'Tournemire' Tradition", undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Report on New England Regional Convention, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Article: "The Grand Orgue de la Basilique du Sacre-Coeur de Montmartre a Paris", undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Notebooks, undated (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - Writings of Others: W.V. Wye Article, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Outline: Sainte Clothilde, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - "Bach: A Modern Experience", undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cesar Franck Article for American Guild of Organists, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - International Romantic Organ Music Symposium, ca. 1980s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "Langlais Honored at Duquesne Convention", March 1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Northland Public Library Dedication, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "Organizing a Junior Choir Festival", undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Record Notes on Kibbie's Tournemire Recording, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Remarks on Music Courses and Music at Dartmouth, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Rough Draft of "L'Orgue Mystique", undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The Second International Academy of Organ, undertermined (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Tournemire Essay Collection Publication Agreement, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 50th Anniversary of Tournemire's Death, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 3, Item 1)
  - Masters Thesis: "Jean Titelouze: A Study in the History of Organ Music", May 1954 (Box 3, Item 2)
  - Dissertation: "Buxheim Organ Book" (2), May 1960 (Box 3, Item 3)
  - "La Musique D'Orgue de Charles Tournemire", Yves Krier, 1979 (Box 3, Item 4)
  - The Diapason, 1991 (Box 14, Oversize 2)
- Research Files, 1889-2013; IV.
  This series contains files of material compiled by Dr. Lord while conducting research on various composers and organs.
  - Research Files, 1.
    - Research Proposals, 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Additional Research, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Additional Research: B.R.Henson, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Additional Research: Flor Peeters, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Specifications of Other Organs (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Research Index, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Specifications of Other Organs, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Research on Beethoven, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Research: Baroque in Germany, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Research on Bach, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Research on Buxtehude, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Research on Monteverdi, Peeters, Widor, 1962-1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Research on Grovewood Gallery, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Notes on Frederick Archer, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Research on Schuebler Chorale, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - General Research, ca. 2005 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Archival Correspondence Photocopies, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Letters concerning the history and installation of a Skinner organ at the Grove Park Inn, Ashville, NC.
    - St. Clotilde Organ Diagnostics, undated (Box 14, Oversize 4)
  - Organ Research Project, 1958-2003; 2.
    - Organ Preservation in the Pittsburgh Area, ca. 1967 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Organ Research Related to the Harmonist Society, 1967-1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Research on the Harvey Joseph Organ, Rochester PA, 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Carnegie Organs (Swedenborg Organ), ca. 1975 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - John Roberts Research, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
    - Christ Church Organ, 1970-1998 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Hooks' Opus 11, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - General Research, ca. 1967 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - General Research, 1968-1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - General Research, 1995-2003 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Pittsburgh Organs, 1968-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Pittsburgh Organs, ca. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Pittsburgh Organs, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Jardine Organs, 1958-1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Musical Courier, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Residence Organs, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Research Indexes (Box 5, Item 1-2)
  - Jean Langlais, 1952-2013; 3.
    - Lord's Writings on Langlais, 1958-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Langlais, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - General Study, 1958-1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Langlais Correspondence, 1989-2013 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Langlais Performance Programs, 1956-2007 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Langlais Sheet Music, 1952-1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Langlais Photos, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Programs in Honor of Langlais, 1955-1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - News Clippings, 1959-1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Duquesne 100 Celebration, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Ann Labounsky, Jean Langlais: The Man and his Music (Ph.D. Dissertation, University of Pittsburgh), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Langlais Obituary Materials, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Jane Redd, Untersuchungen zu deutschen und amerikanischen Kirchenliedern in den Orgelwerken von Jean Langlais (MA Dissertation, Philipps-Universität, Marburg/Lahn), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Marie-Lousie Jacquet Langlais, "Organ Music in France Since Jehan Alain", undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Interview questions for Langlais by Robert Sutherland Lord, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Research notes (typescript and in pencil) on "The Little Organ Book", Jean Langlais, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Research on Langlais's "Passion", undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Jean E. Snyder, Nineteenth and Twentieth Century Organ Music in the University of Pittsburgh Finney Music Library (MA Thesis, University of Pittsburgh), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Jean Langlais the Teacher", Robert Sutherland Lord, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Articles on Langlais by Robert Sutherland Lord, 1968-1995 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Langlais Research Files, ca. 1973 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Printed Materials (newspaper and journal articles), 1958-1998 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Jean Langlais, 3ème Concerto (Reaction), pour orgue, orchestre á cordes et tymbales. Photocopy of Langlais' manuscript (Box 19, Oversize 1)
    - Jean Langlais, 1er concerto pour Clavecin ou orgue et orchestre (photocopy of Langlais' manuscript) (Oversize 2)
  - Maurice Longhurst, 1912-2009; 4.
    - Correspondence with Maurice Longhurst, 1950-1959 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence regarding Maurice Longhurst, 2000-2009 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    - Photographs of Maurice Longhurst, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Study on Maurice Longhurst, ca. 2004 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Dartmouth Records, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Grove Park, ca. 2004 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Berkshire Records Office, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Pack Memorial Library, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Westminster Choir College, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Vanderbilt, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - William Henry Longhurst Obituary Materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Photocopied Newspaper Articles (mostly on Grove Park Inn), undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Sheet Music [Owned by Maurice Longhurst (inscribed on covers)] (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
    - Performance Programs, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - News Clippings, 1947-1953 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Hand Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Legal Pads (loose pages), undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Legal Pad, undated (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
    - Printed Materials (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - F.L. Seely Correspondences, 1926-1927 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Concert scherzo in F: for the organ" (original sheet music by Longhurst), June 1912 (Box 19, Oversize 3)
  - Charles Tournemire, 1889-2012; 5.
    - Biographical Reference Material (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Copies of Tournemire's Letters (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Catalog of Works, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Discography, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Requests to French National Library, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 13)